Ms. Helen Anderson BBUS, PGDip Bus., CBAP.

M 0450 010 325 E Helen.g.anderson@me.com

Helen Anderson

Personal Information

Address: 4/45 Hampton Circuit, Yarralumla ACT 2600

Phone: 0450 010 325

Email: Helen.G.Anderson@me.com

GitHub: https://github.com/grace-anderson

LinkedIn: http://au.linkedin.com/in/handerson1

Citizenship: Australian Citizen, New Zealand Citizen

Security Clearance: Negative Vetting 1 (NV1) (Australia)

Summary

A full-stack developer leveraging background of over fifteen years as a functional business analyst to provide a rounded perspective on application development. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Sydney. Enthusiastic about solving business problems while prioritising user and service experience. Strengths in leadership and teamwork, strategic and design thinking, process analysis and improvement, and requirements elicitation and validation

Technical skills

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, Bootstrap

Portfolio: https://grace-anderson.github.io/portfolio-full-stack/

Recent Development projects

Booknest

Code: https://github.com/grace-anderson/book-nest Deployed: https://the-book-nest.herokuapp.com/

Summary: Book Nest is a proof-of-concept app for book lovers. Readers can find a new favourite book. Book owners can share their e-books. Also, authors can share their stories with the Book Nest community.

- Role: Project team member: Product owner and developer roles
- Tools: node, express, handlebars, express-session, mysql2, sequelize, dotenv, bcrypt
- **Dev:** nodemon, husky, eslint, prettier. **Deployment:** heroku, jawsdb

Tech Blog

Code: https://github.com/grace-anderson/tech-blog
Deployed: https://enigmatic-bayou-29924.herokuapp.com/

Summary: A content management system (CMS)-style blog site where developers can publish their blog posts and comment on other developers' posts

- Role: Sole developer
- Tools: node, express, handlebars, express-session, mysql2, sequelize, dotenv, bcrypt
- Dev: prettier, insomnia
- Deployment: heroku, jawsdb

Employee Tracker

Code: https://github.com/grace-anderson/employee-tracker

 $\label{lem:polyed:command} \begin{tabular}{ll} Deployed: Command line app. See project readme for usage - $$\underline{https://github.com/grace-anderson/employee-tracker/blob/main/README.md}$$$

Summary: A command-line content management system (CMS) used to manage a company's employee database

Role: Sole developer

• Tools: node, npm inquirer, npm figlet, mysql2, sequelize, npm figlet

See my GitHub repositories for a comprehensive list of recent projects

Recent experience

Senior Manager: Business Analyst Synergy Group (March 2021 to present), Canberra ACT

- Australian Communications and Media Authority: Business process analysis and improvement (current engagement, commenced May 2022)
- Service Experience Team, GovERP, Services Australia: Planning and executing user research to inform service design and user experience) (March-May 2022)
- Department of Defence: Elicit, model, and analyse process requirements preliminary to ERP implementation (July 2021-Feb 2022)
- CIO Group, Department of Defence: Develop Innovation Operating Model and Innovation User Guide (April
 June 2021)

Management Consultant: Business Analyst Apis (part of Accenture) (2018-2021), Canberra ACT

- 2IC to Business Team Leader
- Department of Health: Business Analyst in team developing system requirements for NPPs in response to Royal Commission into Aged Care Quality and Safety
- Department of Health: Business Analyst on multiple projects implementing enhancements to My Aged Care system (.net, Siebel)

Business Specialist – Student Administration Charles Darwin University (2011-2018), Darwin NT

• Lead Business Analyst on multiple projects enhancing student management system in collaboration with vendor (Oracle forms and database – vendor Callista (now Tribal), Jira and Confluence)

Qualifications and certifications

2022	Certificate, Full Stack Web Development (University of Sydney)
2022	OMG-Certified Expert in BPM 2 - Fundamental (Business Process Management)
2021	Cert IV in Programming (in progress)
2020	PRINCE2 Practitioner
2019	Certificate IV in Training and Assessment
2017	CBAP (Certified Business Analysis Professional, IIBA, BABOK v.3)
2010	Postgraduate Diploma in Business (Information Systems), University of Auckland, Graduate School of Enterprise
2003	Bachelor of Business (Major Management), First Class Honours, Auckland University of Technology